<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sierra Barkdoll</title>
    <link>https://sierrab1.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sierra Barkdoll</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sierrab1.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bahama Oriole Conservation Research</title>
      <link>https://sierrab1.github.io/projects/bahoresearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sierrab1.github.io/projects/bahoresearch/</guid>
      <description>Project description This research resulted from my time with the Bahama Oriole Project, a collaboration between the Omland Lab of the University of Maryland, Baltimore County, and the Bahamas National Trust. The Bahama Oriole is a critically endangered songbird endemic to Andros island. Known as a brood parasite, the shiny cowbird lays its eggs in oriole nests to be raised by the oriole parents. To ensure parasitism success, cowbirds peck and kill existing oriole eggs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baltimore Wealth and Waste Infographic</title>
      <link>https://sierrab1.github.io/projects/baltimorewealthwaste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sierrab1.github.io/projects/baltimorewealthwaste/</guid>
      <description>Project description This project was in partnership with Benjamin Franklin High School in Baltimore, MD. The goal was to analyze patterns between income, and generated waste and display them in an artistic and readable infographic. We sourced data from GRID - Arendale, BNIA (Baltimore Neighborhood Indicators Alliance), and ACS (American Community Survey). To create the infographic, we used ArcMap and Adobe Illustrator software. We found that higher income neighborhoods are producing more trash than lower income neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art and Human Health in Baltimore</title>
      <link>https://sierrab1.github.io/projects/doesartcleanalleys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sierrab1.github.io/projects/doesartcleanalleys/</guid>
      <description>Project description This project analyzes the relationship between beautification of spaces and public cleanliness. We sourced data from BNAI (Baltimore Neighborhood Indicators Alliance), OpenBaltimoe, and BOPA (Baltimore Office of Promotion and the Arts). To create the infographic, we used ArcMap and Adobe Illustrator software. We found that low-income neighborhoods habe more art murals but also more reports of dirty alleys. If given the resources, further research into this topic may reveal more obvious connections or patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baltimore Vacant Lots Webmap</title>
      <link>https://sierrab1.github.io/projects/qgiswebmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sierrab1.github.io/projects/qgiswebmap/</guid>
      <description>Project description This leaflet webpage was created for an advanced GIS class using QGIS software and the qgis2webmap plug-in. The map shows 2016 data for all vacant lots in Baltimore city. It gives information like neighborhood name and size of vacant lot.
View My Project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronovirus: Showing the spread through density mapping</title>
      <link>https://sierrab1.github.io/projects/coronavirusspread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sierrab1.github.io/projects/coronavirusspread/</guid>
      <description>Project description This research will focus on displaying the spread of the highly-contagious COVID-19 throught the world. To do this, I will create a time-series of density maps that show the density of coronavirus cases for each country every two weeks, starting at patient zero. Click the link below to view my project proposal and data sources.
View My Project Proposal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Sierra</title>
      <link>https://sierrab1.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sierrab1.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>under construction</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>